Guide to the Secular Yiddish Schools in North America Collection M0732
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Yiddish school files
  - Photographs, 1930s-1950s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    5 photographs, including SA Folks Mitlshule farvalters Moeshe Gurin and his wife, early 1940s. Photocopies.
    Photographs.; Gurin, Moshe
  - SYSNA publicity, 1998; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    Westchester Jewish Week, Back to Yiddish schools, Aug 28, 1998. Photocopy, in English about GSF and founding of the SYSNA.
    School Publicity: Newspaper Clippings; Fishman, Gella Schweid
  - Informational material, 1956; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    Why Yiddish for our children, SA Folk Institute. Original, in English and Yiddish, 1956.
  - Obituaries, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    Card of appreciation for condolences from family of Chanan Kiel. Original, in English and Yiddish, undated. Obituary notice, Forverts, Jan. 19, 2001, for Farvalter Elsie Schaefer. Photocopy, in Yiddish and English.
  - Shabbes program, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    SA Folkshule 45. Program for Oneg Shabat. Photocopy, in English and romanized Yiddish, undated.
  - Yiddishe Peretz Shuln, 1949; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    Appeal to parents for donations to the Combined Jewish Appeal, Jewish Peretz School, Montreal. Originals, in Yiddish and English, 1949.
  - SA froyen organizatsye, 1942; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 62, Folder 20)
    Buletin, SA froyen organizatsye. Feb. 1942. Photocopy, in Yiddish.
  - Yorbukh, 1968; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 62, Folder 21)
    Yorbukh gevidmet Shmuel Niger z"l. Sholem Aleichem Folk Institut, 1968. Photocopy, in Yiddish and English.
    Tributes and Anniversary Celebrations; Niger, Shmuel
  - Informational material, 1959; Accession no. 2003-318; 82 p. (Box 62, Folder 22)
    M. Bloshtein, Der yidishe togshul un di yeshivah ketanah. Photocopy, in Yiddish, 1959.
    Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Schools; Bloshtein, M.
  - Bible study, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    Color prints of figures from the Bible. Originals, undated, with English captions.
  - Bible study, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Bible study, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Obituaries, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    Obituaries and memories of the following individuals: Beinfeld, Ben-tsiyon Berland, Sheva Bez, Haim Blank, Yankl Burstein, Esther Dobrushkes, Azaryah Garelik, Yaakov Gebiner, Benyamin Gelbart, Mikhl Goodman, Saul Gottesman, Haim Gubkin, Yisroel Hokhman, Zlatke Kahn, Leybl Kiel, Honen Kling, Yehiel Kopfershteyn, Hershl
  - Obituaries, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    Obituaries and memories of the following individuals: Lehrer, Leybush Levitz, Jacob Liberzon-Serkazsh, Ida Lukomnik, Joanne Mark, Yudl Mayzner, Shloyme Minski, Natan Mlotek, Yosef Novik, Hannah Bracha Pat Pomerantz, Haim Pupko, Bessy Rabiner, Yaakov Leybush Rak, Gitl Shwartz, Haim Simon, Shelomoh Spitalnik, Leybush Stern, Yehiel Tabatshnikov, Yitshak Tolpin, Ezra Weisman, Sender Yunin, Volf
  - Ghetto uprising, 1953-1957; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    3 booklets commemorating anniversaries of the Ghetto uprising, 1940. Originals, 1953, 1956, 1957, in Yiddish.
  - Ghetto uprising, 1966, 1969; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    2 Kemp Hemshekh booklets commemorating anniversaries of the Ghetto uprising. Originals, 1966, 1969, in Yiddish and English.
  - Jewish National Fund, 1965; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    Catalogue of educational materials, Jewish National Fund.
  - Jewish history instruction, 1965; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    Soviet Jewry: The struggle goes on. Original, undated, in English. Suggested outline for teaching of Jewish history in the day school, prepared by Rabbi Zalman F. Ury. 1965, original, in English.
  - Teacher instruction, 1965; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Yiddish women's literature network, 1991; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    Farbindungs bletl far yiddisher froyen-literatur, vol. 1 no. 1. Newsletter [Toronto? 1991]. Original, in English.
    School and Affiliated-Organization Newsletters and Bulletins; Pratt, Norma Fain
  - Correspondence, 1980s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, 1980s. Original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Correspondence, 1980s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    Correspondence, 1970s. Original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    Correspondence, 1960s. Original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Correspondence, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Speech, 1974; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    Speech, An eygener tsu eygene. Undated, in Yiddish, ca. 1974.
  - Addresses, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    Names and addresses.
  - Secularism, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318; 5 p. (Box 65, Folder 7)
    Discourse on the secularist movement. Undated, ca. 1970s.
    Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Schools; Goldberg, Itche
  - Valley Kindershule, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    Publicity relating to Valley Kindershule, Los Angeles. 1960s.
    Administrative / Organizational Materials; Goldberg, Itche
  - Valley Kindershule, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    Meeting minutes of the Council of Kindershules and Mitlshules, Los Angeles. 1960s.
  - Fraynt fun yidish-veltlekher dertsyung, 1962; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    Protokol bukh. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Fraynt fun yidish-veltlekher dertsyung, 1964-1968; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Fraynt fun yidish-veltlekher dertsyung, 1968; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Adminstrative materials, 1950s-1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    Materials relating to Service Bureau for Jewish Education and other organizations. Originals, in English and Yiddish.
  - Concert publicity, 1980s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    Flyers promoting concerts by the Jewish Peoples' Philharmonic Chorus, English, 1989. Lyrics to Unzer shtetl brent, Yiddish and romanized Yiddish, undated ca. 1960s.
    Songs: Music and Lyrics; Goldberg, Itche
  - School for Jewish Knowledge, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    Materials relating to courses at the School for Jewish Knowledge. Originals, in English and Yiddish, ca. 1970s.
    Goldberg, Itche
  - Secular Bar/Bas Mitzvah, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    Materials relating to observance of secular Bar/Bas Mitzvahs. Originals, in English, ca 1960s.
    Secular Bar and Bas/ Bat Mitzvah; Goldberg, Itche
  - Morris Rosenfeld, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    Writings by Morris Rosenfeld. In Yiddish and English.
  - unspecified, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    Writings by Itche Goldberg on problems facing secular Jewish education. English and Yiddish, undated.
  - Informational material, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    Brochure and writings by I. Goldberg on Jewish secular education. Originals, 1970s.
  - Program publicity, 1974; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    Flyer and tickets for program In praise of Yiddish, April 26, 1974, by Friends of Secular Jewish Culture. Originals, in English.
  - Program materials, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    Literary materials for cultural program. Originals, undated, in Yiddish and English.
  - Program materials, 1988; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    Materials for Ich zing Amerike clubs concert, Sunday, June 5, 1988. Originals, in English and Yiddish.
  - Discussion guide, 1954; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    300 years of Jewish settlement in the United States. Jewish Publication and Research Committee, New York, 1954. Original, in English.
    Curriculum Material for Teachers; Goldberg, Itche
  - Correspondence, 1950s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    Correspondence from 1950s. Original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Correspondence, 1950s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1950s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1950s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Jewish history, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Materials for study of Jewish history, including short section from Maimonides, Guide for the perplexed. Originals, undated, in English.
    Pedagogical Materials: Jewish History; Goldberg, Itche
  - Yiddish language, 1974; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    Materials for course in Yiddish taught by I. Goldberg at Queens College. Originals, in English and Yiddish, 1974.
    Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language; Goldberg, Itche
  - Tribute, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    Eulogy for young woman named Ethel. English, undated.
  - Service Bureau of Jewish Education, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Administrative materials, 1970s.
  - 1970s, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Holocaust studies, 1971; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    Materials pertaining to course taught by I. Goldberg in Holocaust studies at Queens College, ca. 1971.
    Pedagogical Materials: Holocaust; Goldberg, Itche
  - Plays, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    Two copies of Shnel loyfn di reder, by I. Goldberg. Undated, in Yiddish. Shtila: The strangest things happen in Los Angeles, by I. Goldberg. English, 1966.
    Creative Arts; Goldberg, Itche
  - Play, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    Shver tsu zayn a yid, by Sholem Aleichem. Typed copy, in Yiddish.
  - Jewish history, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    Materials for teaching Jewish history. Originals, in Yiddish and English, undated
  - Lesson plans, 1961; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    Class plans for Parkway Jewish School, 1961-62. Handwritten, originals, in English.
  - School publicity, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    Brochures and other materials about secular Jewish schools. Originals, undated, in English and Yiddish.
  - Committee for the Advancement of Yiddish, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    Correspondence relating to the Committee for the Advancement of Yiddish. Originals, in English and Yiddish.
  - Meeting minutes, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    Protokol bukh, 1970-1974. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Meeting minutes, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 15)
    Protokol bukh, 1974-1977. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Meeting minutes, 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 67, Folder 16)
    Protokol bukh, 1978. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Speech notes, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    Speech notes, originals, undated, in English and Yiddish.
  - Meeting minutes, 1969, 1982; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    Handwritten and typed meeting minutes, originals, English and Yiddish, 1969, 1982, and undated.
  - Curriculum materials, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    Guides to instruction at Parkway Shule. Original, undated, in English.
  - Report card, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    Blank report card from Parkway Jewish School. English, undated ca. 1960s.
    Diplomas, Report Cards, Graduation Announcements & Certificates; Goldberg, Itche
  - Program publicity, 1950s-1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    Flyers and other publicity for Yiddish cultural programs. Originals, 1950s-1970s.
  - Reports, 1960s-1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    Recommendations by I. Goldberg on improving existing schools and establishing new ones. Originals, English and Yiddish, 1960s-1970s.
  - Outreach, 1950s and 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    Brochures and booklets on the benefits of Jewish secular schools. 1950s and 1960s, in English.
  - Almanakh, 1945, 1953; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    Almanakh fun di idishe kinder shuln. Annual school almanac Brooklyn Committee for Jewish Education, 1945; 1953. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
    Souvenir Journals; Goldberg, Itche
  - Graduation journals, 1960, 1971; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    Mir graduirn, 1960. Nyu-yorker yidishe mitlshul. Original, in Yiddish. Jewish Cultural School of Nassau, 1971. Original, in English.
  - Mailing lists, 1960s-1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    Mailing lists, originals, in English.
  - Mailing lists, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    Mailing labels on carbon paper, originals, in English.
  - Mailing lists, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    Mailing lists and correspondence, undated ca. 1960s and 1970s. In English and Yiddish.
  - Mailing lists, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Holiday materials, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    Holiday materials, 1960s. In English and Yiddish.
  - Diplomas, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    Blank diplomas, undated ca. 1960s and 1970s. In English and Yiddish.
  - Student writings, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    Student compositions, undated. Originals, in English.
  - Lifecycle events, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    Confirmation program, Jewish Community of Cortlandt, NY, 1960. Commencement announcement, Kings Highway Jewish Community School, Brooklyn, NY, 1965. Bar-Bas Mitzvah-Graduation, Peninsula Jewish Folk Shule, Far Rockaway, NY, 1968. Originals, in English.
  - Notebooks, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    Two notebooks, "mayn heft."
  - Address cards, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    Notecards with names and addresses. Undated, in English.
  - Address cards, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Congress for Jewish Culture, 1988; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    Der alveltlekher yidisher kultur-kongres: vos er iz un vos er tut. In Yiddish, undated, ca. 1988.
  - Sholem Aleichem Folk Institute, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    Sheet of letterhead. Original, undated ca. 1950s, in English and Yiddish.
  - Jewish Parent Ed. Comm. of NY, 1950s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    Program aids for Jewish parent groups, by Augusta Saretsky. Original, in English.
    Saretsky, Augusta
  - Maurice Savin WC Branch 1054, 1998; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    1948-1998 Golden anniversary Maurice Savin WC Branch of Northern CA. Original, in English.
  - Ed. Dept. of WC, NY, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    Mameloshn! a program for branches and Yiddish clubs. Original, in English.
  - Hanukah, 1950s-1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    Hanukah materials. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
  - Shabes, 1950s-1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    Shabes materials. Originals and photocopies, in Yiddish and English.
  - Purim, 1950s-1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    Purim materials. Originals and photocopies, in Yiddish and English.
  - Passover, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    Passover materials. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
  - Shavuot, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    Shavuot materials. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
  - Biography, 1999; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    Biography of Jack W. Weinman, 1912-1997 as told by his wife Janice Weinman, April, 1999. English.
    Holiday Materials; Weinman, Jack W.
  - Diplomas, 1940s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    4 diplomas. 1940s. Photocopies, in Yiddish.
  - Curriculum pamphlets, 1950s-1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    Three pamphlets outinling curriculum and school philosophy at SA Folk Shules. Originals, in English and Yiddish.
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    Newspaper clippings regarding secular education. Originals and photocopies, in Yiddish and English.
  - Curriculum, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318; 34 p. (Box 69, Folder 17)
    Guidelines and syllabus for the shuln of the Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring. Adopted by the National Executive Board April 4, 1994. Photocopy, in English.
  - Camp songs, 1960s and 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    Songsters from Boiberik and Kinder Ring. Originals and photocopies, 1960s and 1970s, English and Yiddish.
  - Camp photos, 1920s and 1949; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    Photographs from Camp Boiberik, 1920s and 1949. Photocopies.
  - Camp memories, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    Memoirs from Camp Boiberik and Camp Hemshekh. English.
  - Camp album, 1940s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    Kemp Kinderland albom fun Shloyme Davidman. Original, in Yiddish and English, ca. 1940s.
  - Bible study, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    SA Mitlshul, Halakhah, M. Shtarkman. Undated, in Yiddish, original.
  - Yiddish grammar, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    Der gramatisher min fun zakhverter, fun Yudl Mark. Undated, in Yiddish.
  - Yiddish, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    Yeshiva University review sheets for the study of Yiddish. Undated, in Yiddish.
  - Poem, 1996; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    Dovid Pinski, Shule-himn. In Idisher kempfer, Sept. 1996. Photocopy, in Yiddish.
    School Publicity: Newspaper Clippings; Pinski, Dovid
  - Newspaper clippings, 1990s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    Articles about various shules. Photocopies, in English.
  - Parents bulletin, 1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    5 issues of Parents bulletin, SA Folk Institute. 1963-1967, originals, in English.
  - Songs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    Songs for children. Yiddish, photocopies.
  - Songs, 1946, 1955; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    Songs for children. Yiddish, originals.
  - Yearbook, 1921-1946; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    Sholem Aleichem shul 25 yor yovl-bukh, 1921-1946. Vinipeg, Kanade. In Yiddish, photocopy.
  - Yearbook, 1943; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    Undzer yorbukh in 1943. Kinder-Ring, Philadelphia. In Yiddish, photocopy.
  - Graduation journals, 1967, 1968; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    Graduir-zhurnal, 1967. Fareynikte yidishe mitlshul fun arbeter-ring un sholem aleichem folk institut. In Yiddish, photocopy. Graduir-zhurnal, 1968. Fareynikte yidishe mitlshul fun arbeter-ring un sholem aleichem folk institut. In Yiddish, original.
  - Yearbooks, 1939, 1940; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    Nyu yorker arbeter ring yor bukh, 1939. Original, in Yiddish. Nyu yorker arbeter ring yor bukh, 1940. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Yearbooks, 1941, 1942; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    Nyu yorker arbeter ring yor bukh, 1941. Original, in Yiddish. Nyu yorker arbeter ring yor bukh, 1942. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Yearbooks, 1945, 1947; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    Nyu yorker arbeter ring yor bukh, 1945. Original, in Yiddish. Nyu yorker arbeter ring yor bukh, 1947. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Yearbooks, 1949, 1965; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    Sholem-aleichem folkshul 21 19ter yoyvlbukh, 1949. In Yiddish, photocopy. Sholem-aleichem folkshul 21 36ter yoyvlbukh, 1965. In Yiddish, original.
  - Yearbooks, 1963; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    Yovl-bukh li-khoved 50 yor sholem aleichem folkshuln. 1963, original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Yearbooks, 1961; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    35 yor arbeter ring lerer farband. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Camp songs, 1961; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    Kemp Hemshekh lider bukh, 1961. Original, in Yiddish and romanized Yiddish. Kemp Hemshekh yada, undated ca. 1960s. Original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Albom fun Y.L. Perets, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    An albom fun Y.L. Perets. Undated, in Yiddish. Email message from Bonnie Slotnik describing how she came into possession of the album. English, 2001.
  - Graduation journal, 1931; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    Graduir zhurnal, SA folk shul 19, Brooklyn, NY. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Yearbooks, 1928, 1969; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    Yor bukh, 1928. Sholem aleikhem folk institut. Original, in Yiddish. Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul 21 40th Jubilee Souvenir journal, 1969. Original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Yearbooks, 1956; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    Yor bukh, 1956. Sholem aleikhem folk shul 15, Brooklyn, NY. Photocopy of cover and first 3 pages, in Yiddish.
  - Der Nayer Dor, 1980; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    Der Nayer Dor, published in Montreal, Winter-Spring-Summer 1980. In Yiddish and English, photocopy of cover and 2 p.
  - School publicity, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    Two pamphlets promoting secular Jewish education. Photocopies, in English and Yiddish.
  - Songs, 1939-1940; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    Lomir zingen: shul-lider shul-yor 1939-1940. SA Folk Institut, NY. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Songs, 1932-1933; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    Far unzere kinder: lider gezungen in di klasn un in kindergarten inm lern yor 1933-32. Di naye idishe shul, edmonton. Photocopy of cover.
  - Songs, 1964; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 16)
    Suburban Jewish School song sheets. Originals, in English and romanized Yiddish.
  - Receipt, 2003; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    Letter of receipt from Stanford's Dept. of Special Collections documenting receipt of SYSA materials. Original, English, 2003.
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    Letter of thanks for participating in oral history project. Copy, in Yiddish.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Appleman, Perl Shver
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    Photographs taken during interview. Color, ca. 1993.
    Photographs.; Appleman, Perl Shver
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project. Copy, in Yiddish.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Barlas, Benjamin
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    Photographs taken during interview. Color, 1994.
    Photographs.; Barlas, Benjamin
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    Letter of thanks for participating in oral history project. Copy, in Yiddish and English.